<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on Alexander Pavlenko</title>
    <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on Alexander Pavlenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;div style=&#34;font-size:0.5rem&#34;&gt;&lt;span xmlns:dct=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/terms/&#34; property=&#34;dct:title&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;https://alex.flvr.top/&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Alexander Pavlenko&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 04:20:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alex.flvr.top/blog/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Slicing the Beat</title>
      <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/slicing-the-beat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 04:20:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/slicing-the-beat/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will continue the exploration of Sonic Pi.
So far, I wrote the sequencer, and then found myself reading about the polyrhythms:
 From the philosophical perspective of the African musician, cross-beats can symbolize the challenging moments or emotional stress we all encounter. Playing cross-beats while fully grounded in the main beats, prepares one for maintaining a life-purpose while dealing with life&amp;rsquo;s challenges. Many non-Saharan languages do not have a word for rhythm, or even music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baking the Sonic Pie</title>
      <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/baking-the-sonic-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 21:21:42 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/baking-the-sonic-pie/</guid>
      <description>There is already an article which sings praises to Ruby. And so does the author of Sonic Pi.
 Amazingly, the concept of programming is probably emerged along with the first musical machines. These days, I see how code becomes the universal language which gets ideas across when nothing else can. And the music is the code of feelings. Except when you have &amp;ldquo;amusia.&amp;rdquo;
Today I got curious to explore Sonic Pi and its integration with DAW via MIDI in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>