<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alexander Pavlenko</title>
    <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alexander Pavlenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;div style=&#34;font-size:0.5rem&#34;&gt;&lt;span xmlns:dct=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/terms/&#34; property=&#34;dct:title&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;https://alex.flvr.top/&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Alexander Pavlenko&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 13:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alex.flvr.top/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blurring the Line</title>
      <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/blurring-the-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/blurring-the-line/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The Left Hand of Darkness&amp;rdquo; is a novel published by Ursula K. Le Guin in 1969, featuring an anthropomorphic specie on another planet, where individuals do not have a fixed gender, instead undergoing periodic spontaneous change into male or female, while being asexual most of the time. And they can control this process by using hormones.
I wonder how this piece of science fiction correlates with the actual history:
 Magnus Hirschfeld in 1918 at his Institute for Sexual Science in Berlin was one of the first to offer his patients the means to achieve sex change, either through hormone therapy, sex change operations, or both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slicing the Beat</title>
      <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/slicing-the-beat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 04:20:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/slicing-the-beat/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will continue the exploration of Sonic Pi.
So far, I wrote the sequencer, and then found myself reading about the polyrhythms:
 From the philosophical perspective of the African musician, cross-beats can symbolize the challenging moments or emotional stress we all encounter. Playing cross-beats while fully grounded in the main beats, prepares one for maintaining a life-purpose while dealing with life&amp;rsquo;s challenges. Many non-Saharan languages do not have a word for rhythm, or even music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing the Tree</title>
      <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/climbing-the-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 05:21:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/climbing-the-tree/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I discovered Manfred Max-Neef&amp;rsquo;s Fundamental human needs taxonomy:
 Unlike Maslow&amp;rsquo;s Hierarchy of Needs, which focuses on a hierarchy of psychological needs, Max-Neef talks about needs that are complementary, all of which are necessary to achieve satisfaction.
 Indeed, the Maslow&amp;rsquo;s hierarchy seems to me kind of opinionated and arbitrary.
If only the game was as simple as reaching the imaginary top, somewhere across the infinite ladder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Systems</title>
      <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/mapping-the-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 05:12:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/mapping-the-systems/</guid>
      <description>I think it&amp;rsquo;s cool to be able to create various diagrams just by declaring them in plain text. The first tool which I was using is PlantUML. Then I discovered MermaidJS, which is nicely supported by Typora. It&amp;rsquo;s even possible to render diagrams in the supported browsers. This allows the interactive elements and nice stylings. The graph below is an attempt to visualize the data flow and feedback loops for some of my gadgets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baking the Sonic Pie</title>
      <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/baking-the-sonic-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 21:21:42 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/baking-the-sonic-pie/</guid>
      <description>There is already an article which sings praises to Ruby. And so does the author of Sonic Pi.
 Amazingly, the concept of programming is probably emerged along with the first musical machines. These days, I see how code becomes the universal language which gets ideas across when nothing else can. And the music is the code of feelings. Except when you have &amp;ldquo;amusia.&amp;rdquo;
Today I got curious to explore Sonic Pi and its integration with DAW via MIDI in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing the Hole</title>
      <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/securing-the-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 00:42:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/securing-the-hole/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start by assuming a fictional character Carl who has a bunch of unimportant accounts, perhaps an email full of spam and an online store visited once few years ago. Carl uses the same credentials for each account, and the password is easy to remember – it&amp;rsquo;s his birthday.
Today Carl needs to sign up on a really important website. From muscle memory, the first intention is to reuse the good old login/password.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rationally Grateful</title>
      <link>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/rationally-grateful/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 20:39:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alex.flvr.top/blog/post/rationally-grateful/</guid>
      <description>I have some memories of myself somewhere in space-time getting excited and declaring that all prior disasters were in fact a “blessing in disguise” and without them I thought I would not have this-and-that. I also observed others declaring similar statements. In all those cases a parallel universe where the same and maybe some additional advances are attained without the same disasters – it’s just getting swept under the carpet. Perhaps because in some way it&amp;rsquo;s kind of depressing to think of and it may destroy gratitude which one is trying to express.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>